Her legend begins.
Tomb Raider is a action, adventure, fantasy film directed by Roar Uthaug.
Lara Croft, the fiercely independent daughter of a missing adventurer, must push herself beyond
her limits when she finds herself on the island where her father disappeared.
Lara Croft, played by Alicia Vikander.
Richard Croft, played by Dominic West.
Mathias Vogel, played by Walton Goggins.
Lu Ren, played by Daniel Wu.
Ana Miller, played by Kristin Scott Thomas.
Mr. Yaffe, played by Derek Jacobi.
Tomb Raider is a 2018 action-adventure film directed by Roar Uthaug, with a screenplay by Geneva
Robertson-Dworet and Alastair Siddons, from a story by Evan Daugherty and Robertson-Dworet.
An American and British co-production, it is based on the 2013
video game, with some elements of its sequel.
It is a reboot, and is the third film in the Tomb Raider film series.
The film stars Alicia Vikander as Lara Croft, who embarks on a perilous journey to her
father's last-known destination, hoping to solve the mystery of his disappearance.
Dominic West, Walton Goggins, Daniel Wu, and Kristin
Scott Thomas appear in supporting roles.
Principal photography took place from January to June 2017 at Warner Bros.
Studios, Leavesden in Hertfordshire, England, and Cape Town, South Africa.
The film was also shot on location across London, particularly East London.
The first Tomb Raider film not to be distributed by Paramount Pictures, it was released in the United
Kingdom on March 14, 2018, and in the United States on March 16, 2018, by Warner Bros.
The film grossed $275 million worldwide, approximately the same unadjusted total as the 2001 film of
the same name and more than its 2003 sequel, a figure considered its break-even point.
It received mixed reviews from critics.
A sequel was initially in development with Vikander set to return, but was cancelled in 2022 after
MGM's rights to the Tomb Raider series expired, while Vikander stepped down from the role.
Another reboot film, set to be part of a shared universe that will include a
television series and a video game, is in development at Amazon Studios.
The film explores themes of island, treasure hunt,
remake, female protagonist, heiress.